Notes on Blindness is a drama, documentary film directed by James Spinney.
After losing sight in 1983, John Hull began keeping an audio diary, a unique testimony of
loss, rebirth and renewal, excavating the interior world of blindness.
Following on from the Emmy Award-winning short film of the same name, Notes on Blindness
is an ambitious and groundbreaking work, both affecting and innovative.
Himself (voice), played by John M. Hull.
Herself (voice), played by Marilyn Hull.
John Hull, played by Dan Renton Skinner.
Marilyn Hull, played by Simone Kirby.
Madge Hull, played by Eileen Davies.
Jack Hull, played by David Hobbs.
Notes on Blindness is a 2016 British documentary film
directed by Peter Middleton and James Spinney.
The film profiles writer and theologian John M.
Hull, who became totally blind, just days before the birth of his first
son, after decades of steadily deteriorating vision.
To help him make sense of the upheaval in his life, Hull began documenting his experiences on audio
cassette and wrote his autobiography Touching the Rock: An Experience of Blindness in 1990.
He discusses difficulties such as remembering his families faces, and being unable to find audio versions of the
academic books he wants to read, and thus having to ask friends and family to record them for him.
The film is based upon this work, and his taped diaries and letters.
The directors previously created a 2014 Emmy winning short film
on the same subject, which this film builds upon.
The film won the British Independent Film Award for Best Documentary and received nominations for Best Director,
Breakthrough Producer, Best Achievement in Craft (Joakim Sundström for sound) and the Douglas Hickox Award.
At the 70th British Academy Film Awards, the film was nominated for Best British Film, Best
Documentary and Outstanding Debut by a British Writer, Director or Producer.
It was pitched at Sheffield Doc/Fest's 2012 MeetMarket.
Dan Renton Skinner and Simone Kirby depict John Hull and
Marilyn Hull respectively in the film.
"Notes on Blindness: Into Darkness", an immersive VR experience,
released alongside the film, won a XR Peabody Award in 2021.
The film explores themes of biography, reenactment, blindness, 1980s.
The tone is emotional.